MICHAEL MELLO PAPERS (APAP287) 1800-2008
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Bennie Demps, 1977-1990; 3; 1.8
  - Demps v. Dugger- USCA, 11th Circuit, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Demps v. Dugger- USSA, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Demps - Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Nollie Lee Martin, 1979-1987; 4; 1
  This series contains legal material, correspondence, notes, research files, and correspondence related to the trials of Nollie Lee Martin.
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 1 of 6), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 2 of 6), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 3 of 6), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 4 of 6), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 5 of 6), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Florida v. Martin - 15th Circuit, FL ( 6 of 6), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Martin v. Florida- FLSC, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Martin v. Florida- FLSC, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Martin - Disciplinary Report Worksheet, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Martin v. Wainwright- FLSC ( 1 of 2), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Martin v. Wainwright- FLSC ( 2 of 2), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Martin v. Wainwright- USSC, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Florida v. Martin - 8th Circuit, FL, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Martin v. Dugger- FLSC, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Martin v. Dugger- USDC, S. FL ( 1 of 2), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Martin v. Dugger- USDL, S. FL ( 2 of 2), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Martin v. Dugger- USSC, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Martin v. Florida- FLSC, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Martin v. Wainwright- Research, 1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Martin - Unlabeled Appendix, ca. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- General Case Files, 1977-2004; 5; 10.2
  The series is organized alphabetically by the name of the client.
  This series is made up of legal material and correspondence for cases on which Michael Mello may have had some connection; as counsel, informal advisor, or cases for which he was hired to write Amicus Curiae. Some of the more prominent cases represented in this series include Rolando Cruz, Alvin Ford, Joseph M. Giarratano, and Michael Lambrix.
  - Aubrey Dennis Adams, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aubrey Dennis Adams, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jerome M. Allen, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Phillip Alexander Atkins, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Omar Blanco, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 1 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 2 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 3 of 10), 1983-1984; 1982-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 4 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 5 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 6 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 7 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 8 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 9 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Stephen Todd Booker ( 10 of 10), 1983-1984; 1987-1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Theodore Robert Bundy, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Raymond Robert Clark, 1987-1988; 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - William Carl Coleman, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rolando Cruz, ca. 1988; 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - David Ross Delap, S.R, 1987; 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ernest Charles Dawns, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - William Dvane Elledge, 1983; 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - William Eutzy, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Alvin Bernad Ford, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alvin Bernad Ford, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Charles Kenneth Foster, 1987; 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 1 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 2 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 3 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 4 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 5 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 6 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 7 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bobby Ray Fretwell ( 8 of 8), 1977; 1981-1982; 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 1 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 2 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 3 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 4 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 5 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 6 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 7 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 8 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 9 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 10 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 11 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 12 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Johnny Frank Garrett ( 13 of 13), 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Demetrius Gathers, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Joseph M. Giarratano, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Freddie Lee Hall, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Freddie Lee Hall, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lenson Hargrave, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Ray Allen Harich, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Leonel Torres Herrera, ca. 1992; 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 1 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 2 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 3 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 4 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 5 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 6 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 7 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Jose Martinez High ( 8 of 8), 1982; 1985-1989; 1991; Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Paul Jenings Hill, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - James Earnest Hitchcock, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Carl Jackson, 1988; 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Larry Joe Johnson, 1988; 1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Samuel Bice Johnson, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 1 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 2 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 3 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 4 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Edward Lee Jones ( 5 of 5), 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Edward D. Kennedy, 1992; Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Edward Dean Kennedy - Artwork, Undated (Flat-file 33)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 1 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 2 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 3 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 4 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 5 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 6 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 7 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 8 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 9 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 10 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 11 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 12 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 13 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 14 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 15 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 16 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 17 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cary Michael Lambrix ( 18 of 18), 1984; 1987-1989; 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - George Lemon, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bobby Earl Lusk, 1989-1991; 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Paul Edward Magill, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Paul Edward Magill, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Larry Eugene Mann, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Larry Eugene Mann, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Frank Basil McFarland, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Donald Ray Middlebrooks, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Ralph Mills, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Ralph Mills, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Ralph Mills, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Robert Lacy Parker, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Thomas Pitera, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Thomas Pitera, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Thomas Pitera, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Raleigh Porter, 1991; Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Ricky Bernard Roberts, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Jerry Layne Rogers, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Dan Edward Routly, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Robert Sawyer, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Christopher Simmons, 1997; 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Henry Perry Sireci, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Henry Perry Sireci, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Henry Perry Sireci, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Henry Perry Sireci, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Frank Elijah Smith, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Jimmy Lee Smith, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Dennis Sochor, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Kevin N. Stanford, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Raymound R. Stone, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Raymound R. Stone, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Ronald J. Straight, 1981; 1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Robert Austin Sullivan, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Jesse Joseph Tafero, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - William Wayne Thompson, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - William Wayne Thompson, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - William Wayne Thompson, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Manuel Valle, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - David William Ware ( 1 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - David William Ware ( 2 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - David William Ware ( 3 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - David William Ware ( 4 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - David William Ware ( 5 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - David William Ware ( 6 of 6), 1980; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Jerome Washington, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Johnny Watkins, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Frank Robert West, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Frank Robert West, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Publications, 1979-2006; 6; 4.4
  This series is organized alphabetically by publication.
  This series contains drafts of Mellos various publications, correspondence concerning those publications, copies of newspaper and magazine articles by or about Michael Mello, and advertising and publicity related to his publications. Michael Mello published 6 books, as well as numerous book chapters, journal and newspaper articles, many of which covered similar topics and themes.
  Researchers should note that the original arrangement of this series was minimal. Many of Michael Mellos publications cover similar topics or were revised and used for different publication types. For instance, a book chapter may be a revised version of a previously published journal articles. When possible the archivist has titled the folder to reflect which publication for which the document refers, however, this was not always possible.
  - "Adhering to our views: Brennan and Marshall and the Relentless Dissent to Death as a Punishment" by Michael Mello- Florida State University Law Review, Winter, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Against the Death Penalty - Galley Proofs, ca. 1995 (Flat-file 1)
  - Against the Death Penalty - Galley Proofs in Negatives, ca. 1995 (Flat-file 2)
  - Against the Death Penalty: The Relantless Dissents of Justices Brennan and Marshall- Order Form, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Another Attorney for Life" b Michael Mello, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Ariadne's Provisions: A 'Clue of Thread' to the Intricacies of Procedural Default, Adequate and Independent State Grounds, and Florida's Death Penalty" by Ruthann Robson and Michael Mello- California Law Review, 1988 January (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Borders Book Signing Event, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - " Brief of the National Legal Aid and Detender Association, As Amicus Curiae in support of Respondent in Roper v. Simmons" by Michael Mello- Whittie, Journal of Child and Family Advocacy, Spring, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Capital Punishment as a Legal System: Cases, Stories, and Materials by Michael Mello- Draft (1 of 4), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Capital Punishment as a Legal System: Cases, Stories, and Materials by Michael Mello- Draft (2 of 4), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Capital Punishment as a Legal System: Cases, Stories, and Materials by Michael Mello- Draft (3 of 4), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Capital Punishment as a Legal System: Cases, Stories, and Materials by Michael Mello- Draft (4 of 4), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "'Cold as a Lizard and Ambitious as Lucifer': The Questions I am most Frequently Asked about the unabomber," by Michael Mello- Criminal Law Bulletin, 2000 January- February (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - " The Color of Justice: Race, Class, and Capital Punishment in the United States", 2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - " Counseling Kaczynski"- The National Jurist, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "' Dear Deanna': A Letter on a Lawyer's Life of Death"- Draft, 1993 December 23 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - " Dear Laura": A Letter on a Lawyer's Life of Death- Draft (1 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - " Dear Laura": A Letter on a Lawyer's Life of Death- Draft (2 or 2), ca.1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - " Dead Reckoning: The Duty of Scholarship and the Ethics of Conscientous Abstention From Death Raw Representation" by Michael Mello- Criminal Law Bulletin, 1999 September- October (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Dead Wrong - Button, 1997 (Oversized 1, Item 2)
  - Dead Wrong- Draft (1 of 3), 1995 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Dead Wrong- Draft (2 of 3), 1995 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dead Wrong- Draft (3 of 3), 1995 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dead Wrong- Draft, ca. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts (1 of 3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts (2 of 3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts (3 of 3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dead Wrong Review, 1997 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Death and His Lawyers: Why Joseph Spaziano Owes His Life to the Miami Herald- and Not to Any Defense Lawyer and Judge" by Michael Mello- Vermont Law Review, Fall, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Death Penalty Casebook- Table of Contents, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Death Work- Copy Edits and Page Proofs (1 of 2), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Death Work- Copy Edits and Page Proofs (2 of 2), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Death Work- Draft (1 of 2), 2002 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Death Work- Draft (2 of 2), 2002 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Death Work by Ross Klaven- Screenplay Based on The Wrong Man, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Death Stats, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - " Death-to-Life Overrides: Saving the Resources of the Florida Supreme Court" by Michale L. Radelet and Michael Mello- Florida State University Law Review, Summer, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - " Defunding Death" by Michael Mello- American Criminal Law Review, Summer, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Defunding Death" - Draft, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Defunding Death"- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Defunding Death"- Draft, 1993 November 04 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Defunding Death"- Draft, 1994 August 16 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Defunding Death"- Draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Draft Article for Miami Herald, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - " Ed Kennedy's Rainbow, Steve Booker's Poetry and Dick Jorandby's Soul: Remarks for a Fundraiser for Death Penalty Focus of California" by Michael Mello- Vermont Law Review, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - " Espinosa v. Florida: Constitutional Hurrican or Lamdent Breeze"- Draft, ca.1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - " Executing Rapists: A Reluctant Essay on the Ethics of Legal Scholarship" by Michael Mello- William and Mary Journal of Women and the Law, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - " Executing Those Who Kill Blacks: An Unusual Case Study" by Michael L. Radelet and Michael Mello- Mercer Law Review, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - " Facing Death Alone: The Post- Conviction Attorney Crisis on Death Row" by Michael Mello- The American University Law Review, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - " Innocence and Capital Punishment"- Draft, ca. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "'In the Years When Murder Wore the Mask of Law': Diary of a Capital Appeals Lawyer" by Michael Mello - Vermont Law Review, 2000 Spring (Oversized 1, Item 1)
  - " Is There A Federal Constitutional Right to Counsel in Capital Post-Conviction Proceedings?" by Mihcael Mello- The Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - " Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello, 1979-1990; 1992; Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - " A Letter on a Lawyer's Life of Death" by Michael Mello- South Texas Law Review, 1997 March (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Material Edited out of Unknown Draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - " Mello v. Government- Imposed Mortality"- Loquitur, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1987; 1995-2001; 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - " The Non-Trial of the Century: Representation of the Unabomber" by Michael Mello- Vermont Law Review, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - " On Metaphors, Mirrors, and Murders: Theodore Bundy and the Role of Law" by Michael Mello- New York University Review of Law and Social CHange, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - " On Metaphors, Mirrors, and Murders"- Draft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Outlaw Attorney"- Draft (1 of 2), 1995 December 12 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - " Outlaw Attorney" -Draft( 2 of 2), 1995 December 12 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - " Outlaw Attorney"- Draft, 1995 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - " Outlaw Attorney"- Draft, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Outlaw Attorney"- Draft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Outlaw Attorneys: The Duties of a Law- Abiding Death Raw Post- Conviction Lawyer" by Michael Mello- Yale Version, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - " Outlaw Executive: 'Crazy Joe', The Hypnotized Witness and the Mirage of Clemency in Florida" by Michael Mello- Journal of Contemporary Law, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Photocopies of Book Covers by Michael Mello, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - " Raising Holy Hell: John Brown's Trial Lawyers (and Ted Kaczynski's Lawyer) and the politics od the Instantly Defense" by Michael Mello- Criminal Law Review, 1998 July-August (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - " The Real Capital Punishment: The (Shotgun) Marriage Between Social Science and Litigation, and the Inviting Footnote in Brown v. Texas" by Michael Mello- Criminal Law Bulletin, 1999 March- April (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - " Right to Counsel in Death Penalty" - Draft Outline, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - " Rough Justice: The Capital Habeas Corpus (Anti) Jurisprudence of Judge Robert S. Vance" by Michael Mello- Draft and Research, 1985-1991; Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - " Rough Justice: Reflections on the Capital Habeas Corpus (Anti) Jurispurdence of Judge Robert S. Vance" by Michael Mello- Alabama Law Review, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Statement of Michael Mello Before the Committee on the Judiciary United State Senate Concerning Death Penalty Legislation, 1989 September 27 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Statement of Michael Mello before the Committee on the Judiciary, Vermont House of Representatives, concerning H830-Draft, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Statistics/ Death Penalty by Maxwell/Mello, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - " The Sunshine Executioner: A Review of Among the Lowest of the Dead: The Culture of Death Row by David von Drehle" by Michael Mello- Journal of Contemporary Law, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - " Suspending Justice: The Unconstitutionality of the Proposed Six- Month Time Limit of the Filing of Habeas Corpus Petitions by State Death Row Inmates" by Michael Mello and Donna Duffy- New York University Review of Law and Social Change, 1990- 1991 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - " Taking Coldwell v. Mississippi Seriously: The Unconstitutionality of Capital Statutes that Divide Sentencing Responsibilty Between Judge and Jury" by Michael Mello- Boston College Law Review, 1989 March (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - " Ted Kaczynski's Diary" by Michael Mello and Paul Perkins- Vermont Law Review, Fall, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - The United States of America versus Theodore John Kaczynski: Ethics, Power and the Invention of the Unabomber - Thurlow Gordon Lecture Poster, 1999 (Flat-file 3)
  - Unknown Drafts, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Unlabeled Appendix, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - " Who is the Real 'Outlaw' Here: Joseph Spaziano, Florida Governor Lawton Chilos, or the State and Federal Judiciaries?"- Drafts ( 1 of 3), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 26)